Manan Tyagi

Computer Science Graduate

Email: manantyagi24@gmail.com

Phone: 7550171186

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/manantyagi/

GitHub: https://github.com/manantyagi25 Portfolio: https://manantyagi25.github.io/

A creative and enthusiastic engineering student from Vellore Institute of Technology. Experienced in graphics and UI/UX designing, Java, Android, and game development in Unity. The ultimate career goal is to work as a senior software developer in a reputed company.

EDUCATION

1. CSE, B.Tech

Vellore Institute of Technology, Chennai 07/2016 – 05/2020 **CGPA:** 8.10

2. Class 12th

Kendriya Vidyalaya No. 1, SVN, Vizag 2014 – 2016 **Percentage:** 91.8%

3. Class 10th

Kendriya Vidyalaya Ballygunge, Kolkata 2013 – 2014 **CGPA**: 10

WORK EXPERIENCE

1. Freelance Android App Development 02/2021 – Present Work from home

Taj Holiday Village Resort & Spa, Goa

- Built an Android app using Firebase to facilitate hotel staff to report any concerns, and also track and close those concerns.
- Also has the feature to view and download reports of active and closed concerns in Excel format on one button click.

2. Game Development in Unity Internship 05/2019 – 06/2019 Bangalore

KnowledgeLens

- Contributed to an augmented reality (AR) application to be deployed for industrial usage for remotely monitoring machine health and working, designed to compete with the existing SCADA systems.
- Also developed the UI/UX for the app, which was appreciated by the team, the client, and the company CEO.

PROJECTS

1. Yellow Pages (02/2021 - Present)

- A professional Android app requested by a hotel in Goa to facilitate issues reporting and tracking. The app is under review currently and awaiting approval.
- Currently only supporting one hotel, but can be extended for multiple hotels, when required.

2. Socialize Chat Zone (10/2020 - 11/2020)

 A chat app that allows users to chat with their friends. Uses accounts created in Socialize app.
Made using Android and Firebase.

3. Socialize (9/2020 – 10/2020)

 A social media app to facilitate users to connect to one another by sharing posts. Made using Android and Firebase.

4. ARphabets (07/2019 - 11/2019)

 Built an interactive system in Unity to learn the alphabets using Augmented Reality.

5. Storage Virtualization Control Panel (07/2019 – 11/2019)

- Built a User Interface for the simulation of creation, modification and deletion of virtual storages in cloud systems.
- The major part of this project was the UI/UX development, done in Invision Studio.

6. CodeMART (07/2017 – 11/2017)

- Online Coding Learning platform for learning through the use of videos and quizzes.
- UI/ UX Development through Adobe XD.

SKILLS

•	Android	****
•	Java	****
•	Unity	****
•	C++	***
•	Adobe XD	***
•	InVision Studio	****